<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The DevOps Lab (Channel9) on DevOps Rob</title><link>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/</link><description>Recent content in The DevOps Lab (Channel9) on DevOps Rob</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part 1 | Zero Trust Security (ZTS) with HashiCorp and Azure: Automating Secrets Management</title><link>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/part1-automating-secrets-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/part1-automating-secrets-management/</guid><description>In Part 1 of 2 of our HashiCorp series, Rob Barnes from HashiCorp will discuss how you can leverage identity-based AuthN to Vault using Azure Active Directory and learn why centralising identity management at scale is critical to implementing Zero Trust Security (ZTS).</description></item><item><title>Part 2 | Zero Trust Security (ZTS) with HashiCorp and Azure: Automating Secrets Management</title><link>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/part2-automating-secrets-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/part2-automating-secrets-management/</guid><description>In Part 2 of 2 of our HashiCorp series, Rob Barnes from HashiCorp is back to discuss why a key component for zero trust security (ZTS) is reducing secrets sprawl for machine-to-machine authorization. Hear from Rob to learn about using dynamic secrets generation for Azure Resources with Vault.</description></item><item><title>Workload authentication to HashiCorp Vault with Azure IMDS and managed identity</title><link>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/workload-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://devops-rob.github.io/posts/the-devops-lab-videos/workload-authentication/</guid><description>In this episode, Rob Barnes from HashiCorp is back to show practitioners how to enable and configure the Azure auth method in HashiCorp Vault, as well as how applications hosted on Azure VMs can authenticate using a combination of managed identity and the Instance Metadata Service (IMDS).</description></item></channel></rss>